Gai... Don't tell me you're?
No. This is...
Dan!
What the hell is this?!
≪♪♪（歌声）
♪♪～
（男性）ううっ！　あっ！！　うわー！！
T-Terrorists, eh? St-State your conditions!
≪（涯）うわぁぁぁぁ！！
What do you want?
I'm GHQ's Supreme Commander...
（涯）あぁぁ！　あぁ…！
あっ…！　くぅぅ！
Unit number 823.
（いのり）涯。　まさか…！？
It's the same number as my birthday.
（涯）違う。　これは…。
Don't you get it?
（どよめき）
I see... you don't even get it.
（ダン）うおぉ！　おっ！！
（ヤン）ダン！
You two are obscene!
（ダン）何なんだ　これは！？
うっ…！！
So, everything that makes me whole
Ima kimi ni sasageyou
（ヤン）テ…　テロリストか？
よ…　要求を言え。　何が望みだ？
私は　ＧＨＱ最高司令官で…。
I'm yours
（ダリル）「機体番号８２３」→
「僕の誕生日と同じナンバーだ」
（ダリル）「分からないの？
そう。　分からないのかよ」
Nee, kono sekai ni wa takusan no
shiawase ga arun da ne
（ダリル）「汚らしいんだよ！」
（ダリル）あんたたちは！！
（ダリル）「うわぁぁぁ！」
Itsuka futari nara
♪♪～
Dare ka ga kimi no koto
wo usotsuki to yonde
Kokoro nai kotoba de
kizu tsukeyou to shite mo
Sekai ga kimi no koto wo
shinjiyou to mo sezu ni
Ibara no kanmuri wo kabuseyou to shite mo
Watashi wa kimi dake no mikata ni nareru yo
Sono kodoku itami wo watashi wa shitte iru
So, everything that makes me whole
Ima kimi ni sasageyou
sympathetic vibration
（茎道）私は
ＧＨＱ　アンチボディズ局長→
This is Shuichiro Keido,
chief of GHQ's Anti Bodies unit.
茎道　修一郎だ。→
テロリストの奇襲により→
I'm afraid that Major General
Yan has died tragically today
ヤン少将は
無念の戦死を遂げられた。
in a surprise terrorist attack.
（ローワン）「ご苦労だったな。
ダリル少尉」
You worked hard, Lieutenant.
（茎道）軍紀にのっとり→
In accordance with military regulations,
as the highest-ranking official at the scene,
臨場している最先任士官である
私が　以降の指揮を執る。→
I will be assuming command.
These terrorists have launched
a despicable, large-scale viral attack
テロリストは　卑劣にも
関東全域にウイルスを使った→
大規模テロを仕掛けてきた。→
against the entire Kanto region.
This is a Level 1 state of emergency.
これは第１級非常事態である。
As of this moment, all military personnel
are under Anti Bodies command.
現時刻より　全ての軍は
アンチボディズの指揮下に入れ。
繰り返す！
これは第１級非常事態である。
I repeat: This is a Level 1 state of emergency.
（嘘界）あなたにも
協力していただきますよ。
We'll avail ourselves of
your help as well, Dr. Ouma.
桜満博士。
（ダン）やめろーっ！！
Don't you dare!
Haruka! Stop!
（茎道）春夏！　止まれ！！
How dare you point your gun at a woman?!
女性に銃を向けるとは。
見損なったぞ　スカーフェース！
I expected more from you, Scarface!
A bit behind, aren't you? I expected
more from you from the beginning.
今ごろですか。　私は　最初から
あなたを見損なっていましたよ。
≪（銃声）
[TEL]（シャッター音）
（茎道）移動するぞ　嘘界少佐。
Time to move, Major Segai.
Yes, Sir.
了解しました。
At approximately 3:40 pm,
a terrorist group calling itself Funeral Parlor
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]（アナウンサー）先ほど　１５時４０分ごろ→
羽田空港において　葬儀社と名乗るテロリストグループが→
carried out a large-scale attack
at Haneda Airport using the Virus.
ウイルスを使った
大規模なテロを行いました。
- That's wrong!
- In response, the government
has issued a special contagion alert,
（集）違う。　葬儀社は
バイオテロなんて　しない！
- Funeral Parlor would never use bioterrorism!
- In response, the government
has issued a special contagion alert,
（鶫）「当たり前でしょ！」
- Well, duh.
- and citizens are...
鶫？
（鶫）「何やってるのよ　集」
Tsugumi?
What are you doing, Shu?
They've taken us all down.
And I can't get in touch with Gai or Inoreen...
（鶫）こっちは　みんな
やられちゃった。→
涯とも　いのりんとも
連絡　取れないし→
このままじゃ　私たち…。
At this rate, we'll all...
みんなが…！
You guys...
It's your fault, Shu.
Because you wouldn't come!
（鶫）あんたのせいよ　集！
あんたが来ないから。→
ヴォイドを使わないから！！
Because you wouldn't use Voids!
[ﾏｲｸ]（生徒）特級防疫警報が
発令されました。→
A special contagion alert has been issued.
まだ避難していない
生徒の皆さんは…。
All students who haven't yet evacuated,
（花音）祭と桜満君　見なかった？
- Have you seen Hare and Ouma?
- please move to your designated shelter blocks.
（颯太）集なら
先に帰ったんじゃないか？→
- Shu probably went home early.
- please move to your designated shelter blocks.
- I repeat: A special contagion alert has been...
- He was looking pretty sick earlier.
さっき　調子　悪そうだったから。
≪（ハウリングの音）
Um, can you hear me?
[ﾏｲｸ]あの…。　聞こえますか？
"The shelter is this way."
[ﾏｲｸ]これから　名前を言う人。
If they can hear this broadcast,
I'd like the following people to,
um... to report to the Film Club room.
[ﾏｲｸ]この放送が聞こえていたら
えっと…　映研部室まで来てほしい。
こんなときだけど
頼みたいことがあるんだ。
I know it's a bad time, but I have a favor to ask.
《みんなのヴォイドを使って
いのりと涯を助ける》
I'll use their Voids to save Gai and Inori.
I don't know whether I can really
do it or not, but I've got no choice.
《やれるかどうか分からないけど
やるしかない》
The leader, Gai Tsutsugami,
is on the run with one accomplice.
リーダーの恙神　涯は
他１名と共に逃走中。→
Funeral Parlor's remaining arsenal
consists of one large trailer, one Endlave,
葬儀社の残存戦力は→
大型トレーラー１。
エンドレイヴ１。→
and a fighting force of about
eight people west of the terminal.
ターミナル西方に
約８名の戦闘集団を確認。
They've completely lost
their chain of command now.
（ローワン）これで　彼らの指揮系統は
完全に失われたはず。　局長は？
Where's the Chief?
先ほど　六本木に到着されました。
He just arrived in Roppongi.
（嘘界）作戦どおり　葬儀社の戦力は羽田に集中したようですね。
It seems Funeral Parlor's forces
are concentrated at Haneda,
just as planned.
嘆きの川を渡るときが来たのだ。→
It's time to cross the river of lamentation...
真名。
...Mana.
What's this "favor," Shu?
（颯太）何だよ？　集。
頼みたいことって。
（花音）防疫警報が出てるの
知ってるよね？
You know we're under a contagion alert, right?
Mm-hmm. But...
うん。　でも　僕は…。
僕は　羽田に行きたいんだ。
But I want to go to Haneda.
（亞里沙）空港に？
（花音）外には　ウイルスが出てるのよ。
To the airport?
The Virus is out there, you know!
There are... people I want to save at Haneda.
羽田に…　助けたい人がいるんだ。
でも　僕１人じゃ無理で。
But I can't do it by myself...
so, I thought if I could get your help...
その…。
みんなに手伝ってもらえれば…。
So you intend to use people like tools again, huh?
（谷尋）そうやって
また　人を道具にするつもりか。
Yahiro!
谷尋君！
（颯太）何だよ？　道具って。
What do you mean, "tools"?
Good question.
Maybe Shu will answer that for you.
さあな。
集なら答えてくれるんじゃないか？
（谷尋）なあ　集。
Huh, Shu?
≪（倒れる音）
あっ…！
真名…。　俺は　また　お前に…。
Mana... We're doing this again?
涯！　私なら止められる。
Gai.
I could stop this.
It's too late. After it's crystallized
this much, even your blood won't...
ここまで結晶化したら
お前の血でも　もう…。
No, I mean I could sing that song...
違う。　あの歌を。
≪（足音）
（春夏）いのりちゃん！？
ハッ！
Inori?!
色々と聞きたいことはあるけど
まず教えて。
I have a lot of questions for you,
but for now tell me this:
集は　どこ？　一緒じゃないの？
Where is Shu? Isn't he with you?
We left him behind.
あいつなら置いてきた。
今は　学校にいるはずだ。
He should be in school
right now. No need to worry.
心配ない。
But... he'll come.
でも　来る。
I'm sure that... Shu will...
集は　きっと…。
（亞里沙）道具というのは
どういうことかしら？
Might I ask what he means by "tools," exactly?
こんな状況で　助けに行かなくちゃいけない人って誰なの？
Who is it you have to go save,
even when it's this dangerous?
Don't tell me it's Inori? Is it Inori?!
ひょっとして　いのりちゃん？
いのりちゃんなのか？
（祭）みんな
いっぺんに言わないで。
Don't all go at him at once, guys.
Shu will answer you. Right?
集は　ちゃんと答えるから。
ねっ。
《涯なら　こんなとき
どうするだろう？》
What would Gai do at a time like this?
《有無を言わさず行動する？》
Would he act without taking "no" for an answer?
もう　時間ないのよ。　逃げなきゃ。
There's no time! We have to run!
Come on, tell us, Shu! We're friends, aren't we?
話してくれよ　集。
俺たち　友達だろ！
桜満　集君。　あなたには→
Shu Ouma, I believe you have a duty to answer.
答える義務が
あると思うんだけれど。
Would he get some consensus first?
《根回しを済ませておく？》
Would he trick them into doing what he wanted?
《人をだまして
思いどおりにさせる？》
《それとも　強引に
命令してしまうんだろうか…》
Or would he just force orders on them?
《それは　涯のやり方だ》
That's Gai's way of doing things. I can't be like Gai.
《僕は　涯みたいには　できない》
《僕は　僕にできる　やり方で
やるしかない！》
I'll just have to do things the way I can do them.
祭。
何？
Hare.
What?
I'm about to do something a little scary to you.
これから　僕は
君に　ちょっと怖いことをするよ。
でも　何も心配しなくていい。
危険は　ないから。
But you don't have to worry. You're not in danger.
Okay. Go ahead.
うん。　いいよ。
お…　おい！
H-Hey!
（祭）うっ…！
What is this?!
これは…！
♪♪～
《包帯…。　祭らしいな》
Bandaging... That's like you, Hare.
祭　どうしちゃったの？
What happened to Hare?
It's okay. She'll wake up when I put this back.
大丈夫。
これを戻せば　目が覚めるから。
ど…　どうなってんだよ　集。
Wh-What's going on, Shu?!
I trust you'll explain, Ouma?
（亞里沙）
説明してくれるのよね　桜満君。
This is a Void. It's someone's heart given form.
これはヴォイド。
人の心を形にしたものだよ。
だから　人によって
形と効果は違ってくる。
So its shape and effects will be
different depending on the person.
（花音・颯太）あっ！
No way!
嘘ぉ…！
あれ？　私…。
Huh? What did I?
It's okay. I used your Void just now.
大丈夫？
今　君のヴォイドを使ったよ。
えっ？
私　どんなだった？
What did mine look like?
It was kind, like you.
祭らしい
優しいヴォイドだったよ。
忘れちゃってると思うけど→
I'm pretty sure you've forgotten,
颯太と谷尋
それに　供奉院さんからは→
but I've drawn out yours before, too,
Souta and Yahiro... and Kuhouin.
前に取り出したことがあるんだ。
俺らからも？
Us too?
It felt like I'd peeked into
your hearts without asking, so...
君たちの心を
勝手に盗み見た気がして→
I've felt guilty all along.
ずっと後ろめたかった。
ごめんなさい。
I'm sorry.
That's not all, though, is it?
（谷尋）それだけじゃないだろう。
「僕は　その力を　テロリストを
手伝うために使いました」だろ？
You forgot the " I used that
power to help terrorists" part.
谷尋…。
Yahiro...
言えよ。
Say it. Say who you want to go save now, too.
これから
助けに行きたい人ってのも。
That's right. Gai and Inori...
everyone in Funeral Parlor.
そう。　涯と　いのり…。
葬儀社のみんなだ。
いのりちゃんも葬儀社！？
Inori's in Funeral Parlor too?
答えろよ　集。
Answer me, Shu: Why do you
want to save people like that?
そんなやつらを
どうして助けたい？
When you couldn't even save Jun!
潤のことも
助けられなかったのに！
Those guys are terrorists!
テロリストなんだろ　そいつらは！
僕にも何かできるって
信じてくれたから。
It's because they believed that
there was something I could do!
葬儀社のみんなが　いなかったら→
If it hadn't been for Funeral Parlor,
I'd still be someone who didn't matter!
今でも
僕は　いなくていい人間だった。
そのみんなが困っていて
僕には　やれることがある！
Now they're in trouble,
and there's something I can do to help!
So please!
だから　お願いします！
Okay, then! Let's go!
よし！　行こう。
ここにいたって
無事って保証は　ないんだろ。
No guarantee we'll be safe here anyway, right?
Might as well move, then!
だったら　動く方がいいじゃん。
フッ。
（祭）颯太君らしいね。
That's just like you, Souta.
私にも
無関係というわけではなさそうね。
It sounds like it's not " someone
else's business" for me either.
All right!
（颯太）よっしゃ！
すっげえの出してやるぜ！
Thanks, Yahiro.
ありがとう　谷尋。
あっ…。
俺だって
潤が必要としてくれなければ→
Well, I never would have mattered
either, if Jun hadn't needed me.
とっくに
いなくていい人間だった。
同じだろ　お前も。
You're the same, aren't you?
これが　コキュートスに続く
地獄の門ですか？
Is this the Gate of Hell that leads to Cocytus?
いいや。→
No.
For me, this is the Gate of Heaven.
これは　私にとっては
天国の門だよ。
あっ！
I can't hold out very long!
長くは持たないぞ。
まさか　こんな状況で
実践テストとは思わなかったけど。
I never thought I'd do the practical
test under these circumstances...
Will Shu come?
《集は来る？》
Do... I want him to come?
《来てほしいの？　私が…》
I didn't know there was a pathway here.
（颯太）
こんなとこに　道があったんだ。
（谷尋）これなら　軍に止められずに空港近くまで行けるな。
We should be able to get close to the airport
without getting stopped by the army this way.
集。　もう　大丈夫ね。
Shu.
You're all right now, right?
Mm-hmm.
うん。　ありがとう。
Thank you. I owe it to you, Hare.
祭のおかげだよ。
Dammit, dammit, dammit!
（アルゴ）チキショー　チキショー
チキショー！
（綾瀬）「キャー！
ああっ！　あっ！」
（綾瀬）ああっ！　集…。
Shu!
ハァ…　ハァ…。
Almost there... Almost there!
（春夏）もう少し。
もう少しで…。
（春夏）開いた！
It's open!
Inori!
いのりちゃん！
Shu...
集…。
♪ I'll never be loved by you again ♪
♪♪「もう　あなたから
愛されることも」
♪♪「必要とされることもない」
♪ Or needed by you again, either ♪
♪♪「そして　私は
こうして　一人ぼっちで」
♪ And so here I am, all alone ♪
♪♪「あなたは　いつも
そうやって　私を」
♪ You always do that, make me angry ♪
♪ And then make me cry in the end ♪
♪♪「怒らせて　最後に泣かすんだ」
いのり…！
Inori.
♪ But when you said "I'm sorry" afterward, ♪
（春夏）ゲノムレゾナンスが
３，０００を超える！？
Genomic resonance is exceeding 3000?!
♪♪「ごめんねっていう　その顔」
♪ I always loved the look on your face ♪
何だと！？
What?!
（綾瀬）ハッ！　この歌…。
This song?
いのりだ！
It's Inori.
えっ？
いのりが歌ってる！
Inori's singing!
There's a barricade up ahead!
（鶫）「前方　バリケードあるよ！」
Halt!
≪止まれ！！
侵入者は実力排除するぞ！
We'll eliminate all intruders by force!
Kuhouin!
供奉院さん！
（亞里沙）お使いなさい。
Use it!
くっ…。　撃てーっ！
Fire!
♪♪～
♪ Yes, hold me tight as you can and don't let go ♪
Barricade 3 has been breached!
（通信士）
３号バリケード　突破されました！
Is it an Endlave?
（ローワン）エンドレイヴか？
（通信士）それが…。
Is it an Endlave?
♪ I want to be in your arms ♪
Well, er...
♪♪～
♪ We'll sleep with our foreheads pressed together ♪
（花音・祭）キャー！
あっ　橋が…！
The bridge!
♪♪～
涯なら引かない。
祭！
Gai wouldn't retreat.
Hare!
♪♪～
Wow.
すごい…。
（颯太）うじゃうじゃ来たー！
They're swarming us!
♪♪～
Souta, it's your turn!
颯太！　君の出番だ！
（颯太）えっ　俺！？
Me?
♪♪～
[無線]（通信士）第４エンドレイヴ小隊　全滅。
２号ゲート　突破されました！
Endlave Platoon 4 has been completely wiped out!
♪ You always do that, make me angry ♪
Gate 2 has been breached!
You can't stop one measly buggy?
（ダリル）たかがバギーを
止められないって　無能過ぎるだろ。
♪ And then make me cry in the end ♪
How incompetent can you be?
Swap me into the nearest unit.
一番近い機体にスワップだ。
♪ But when you said "I'm sorry" afterward, ♪
I'll bring them down.
僕が仕留めてやるよ。
♪ I always loved the look on your face ♪
見つけた！
鶫。　レーダー棟だ！
There you are!
Tsugumi! The radar building!
Aye-aye! We'll take the shortest route!
（鶫）「アイ。　最短距離で行くよ！」
Hold on, everybody!
（鶫）「みんな　つかまってて！」
（大雲）集が来る！
Shu is coming!
（アルゴ）ケッ。　遅いんだよ。
You're late, dude.
Inori!
いのりー！
♪♪「離さないで
ぎゅっと　そう思いっきり」
♪ Yes, hold me tight as you can and don't let go ♪
♪ I want to be in your arms ♪
（ダリル）「うおーっ！」
うわあー！
♪ We'll sleep with our foreheads pressed together ♪
くっ…。
谷尋！
Yahiro?
これが
お前の　やれることなんだろ？
This is "what you can do," right?
うん。
Come on out, you little rats.
（ダリル）
「出てこいよ　ねずみども」
（ダリル）「ぐあーっ！！
お前だったのか　顔なし！」
So it was you, faceless bastard?!
うおおぉぉぉ！
うっ。　あぁ…。
≪（爆発音）
バカが。　俺が　せっかく…。
Moron. Just wasting my effort...
Inori!
いのりーっ！！
いのり。
Inori.
Shu!
集…！
うっ！　あっ…。
あぁぁぁ！
あっ…　いのり！！
Inori!
I'm very disappointed in you.
（ユウ）
あなたには　がっかりですよ。
あ…。
（ユウ）王の器を得ながら
いつまでも　うつろなままで。→
You gain what could be your throne,
and then you just leave it empty forever.
ここで　お別れです。
This is where we part.
さようなら　桜満　集。
Goodbye, Shu Ouma.
（嘘界）歌が…。
（茎道）止まったな。
The song...
It stopped.
あっ…！
涯！
Gai!
だから　ほっとけないんだ…
お前は…。
This is why I can't leave you...
to your own devices...
涯…。　しっかり！
Gai! Hang on!
うっ…。
涯…。　涯！
Gai...
Gai! Gai!
涯！！
♪♪～
Mou anata kara ai sareru koto mo
Hitsuyou to sareru koto mo nai
Soshite watashi wa kou shite hitori bocchi de
Ano toki anata wa nante itta no?
Todokanai kotoba wa chuu wo mau
Wakatteru no ni kyou mo shite shimau
Kanawanu negaigoto wo
Hanasanaide gyutto te wo nigitte ite
Anata to futari tsuzuku to itte
Tsunaida sono te wa atatakakute yasashikatta